

NOUMAN JAVED Frontend Developer

- 🛛 Islamabad, Pakistan
- ☑ noumanmalik960@gmail.com
- +92 (304) 5681874

SOCIALS

- in @noumanjaved
- noumanmalik960
- @noumanmalik960

PROFILE

I am a Javascript developer working in ReactJS mainly, having more than a year experience working in React based environment. In my last job I woked in the frontend of a commercial app using React Native and learned a lot. I enjoy facing problems and solving them by pressing a bunch of keys!. Currently learning AWS Amplify.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in ComputerScience

Islamic University, Islamabad 2016 - 2021

Faculty of Science

IMCB F/7-3, Islamabad

2013 - 2015

MATRICULATION

IMCB F/7-3, Islamabad 2011 - 2013

SKILLS

- HTML
- REACTJS |
- CSS

IA\/ASCDIDT

REACT
 NATIVE

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Frontend

September 2021 - Present | Stack One (Pvt) Ltd

Currently working as a Software Engineer - Frontend at Stack One (Pvt) Ltd.

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER

March 2021 - June 2021 | TechChaps

I got a chance to work with Leisester based software company as Jr. Frontend Developer at *TechChaps* in March 2021 as a React Native developer. I was put in a fast pace team where I build UI of a mobile app and handled API consumption, working closely with the Backend team. (I can show my work that I did there when needed)

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Nov 2020 - Dec 2020 | Freelance

I worked with a friend who was doing freelancing and my job was to convert PSD to HTML where I used HTML, CSS, JS and ReactJS to make it Reactive.

CERTIFICATES

Cloud Native and Mobile Web - PIAIC

It is a two year cloud native online course where I am learning about latest technologies. So far I have learned Javascript, ReactJS, Gatsby, Git/GitHub, Linux OS, PWA and much more and its still going on.

PROJECTS

ightarrow A Gatsby-Contentful site

A content consuming site made using GatsbyJS for the frontend, headless CMS Contentful to create and consume content, redux for store management and deployment and CI/CD using Netlify. This project is not complete yet. Here's the link of its deployment: youshopweship

\rightarrow Expense Tracker

A simple expense tracker PWA made in React using useState, contextApi, service workers and more. It was deployed using GitHub Actions CI/CD. expensetracker

→ Quiz App

A quiz app, made using react hooks, TypeScript, Material UI, consuming open source quiz API, implemented as a PWA. Deployed on Netlify using GitHub Actions CI/CD. quizapp

There are a lot more projects in my github profile...

LANGUAGES